Edward Vaisman

📞 (+1) 647-219-6236 | 🖂 vaismanedward@gmail.com | 🚍 edwardvaisman.ca | 🛅 edwardvaisman | 🕟 eddyv

Professional Summary

Software developer with 8 years of professional experience and a potent interest for event-driven systems. Proficiency in operating multi-region distributed streaming platforms like apache kafka on aws. Extensive software development life cycle experience exercised from start to finish along with prominent communication skills and constructive attitude.

Professional Experience

Confluent STAFF PARTNER INNOVATION ENGINEER Toronto, ON

Oct 2022 - Current

- Architected and secured a robust, multi-datacenter Kafka infrastructure, including add-ons like Confluent Schema Registry, MirrorMaker2, and Kafka
- Developed automation for provisioning, maintaining, and monitoring Kafka environments using the HashiCorp stack.
- Designed, implemented, and operated multi-datacenter Kafka infrastructure along-side kafka add-ons such as Confluent Schema Registry, MirrorMaker2,
- · Implemented observability solutions, creating real-time monitoring dashboards to track Kafka cluster connectivity, security, and performance. (DataDog, ElasticSearch, Prometheus, Grafana)
- Built self-serve GitOps tools to increase speed and productivity of developers using the kafka platform. (Topic Management, ACL Management, Kafka Connect Cluster Deployment, KSQL Deployment, Self-Hosted GitHub Runners, etc...)
- · Increased our PaaS offerings by building an in-house CLI to interact with our private cloud infrastructure to deal with secret management, volume management, application deployment. (Typer CLI, Nomad APIs, Vault APIs)
- · Optimized Kafka performance by identifying bottlenecks and implementing throughput enhancements.
- · Ensured system reliability through rigorous disaster recovery testing and routine backup and restoration exercises.
- · Educated staff on Kafka architecture, Schema Registry, and event-driven design principles, fostering company-wide adoption of best practices.

Kafka Flink Terraform Java Vert.x



Toronto, ON

Nov 2020 - Oct 2022

- Architected and secured a robust, multi-datacenter Kafka infrastructure, including add-ons like Confluent Schema Registry, MirrorMaker2, and Kafka
- Developed automation for provisioning, maintaining, and monitoring Kafka environments using the HashiCorp stack.
- Designed, implemented, and operated multi-datacenter Kafka infrastructure along-side kafka add-ons such as Confluent Schema Registry, MirrorMaker2,
- Implemented observability solutions, creating real-time monitoring dashboards to track Kafka cluster connectivity, security, and performance. (DataDog, ElasticSearch, Prometheus, Grafana)
- · Built self-serve GitOps tools to increase speed and productivity of developers using the kafka platform. (Topic Management, ACL Management, Kafka Connect Cluster Deployment, KSQL Deployment, Self-Hosted GitHub Runners, etc...)
- · Increased our PaaS offerings by building an in-house CLI to interact with our private cloud infrastructure to deal with secret management, volume management, application deployment. (Typer CLI, Nomad APIs, Vault APIs)
- · Optimized Kafka performance by identifying bottlenecks and implementing throughput enhancements.
- Ensured system reliability through rigorous disaster recovery testing and routine backup and restoration exercises.
- · Educated staff on Kafka architecture, Schema Registry, and event-driven design principles, fostering company-wide adoption of best practices.

Kafka Terraform Nomad Vault SaltStack Python Bash Docker GitHub Actions Prometheus Grafana DataDog ElasticSearch



Toronto, ON

Sept 2018 - Oct 2020

- · Played a key role in advancing the bank's Customer Intelligence Platform by delivering a near real-time solution to provide the business with a unified view of customer interactions and enhance customer experience.
- · Onboarded, trained, and mentored developers, ensuring comfortability and expertise in distributed systems, Git Flow, Dockerized deployments, and event-driven architecture.
- · Designed and implemented a secure, field-level encrypted real-time data pipeline enabling seamless data transfer between on-premises and cloud-based Kafka clusters (AWS).
- · Developed and optimized real-time streaming data pipelines to facilitate reliable data exchange across systems and applications.
- Created real-time streaming applications to transform and react to data streams, driving actionable insights.
- Automated workflows and integrations to enhance operational efficiency and effectiveness.
- · Produced high-quality software implementations, adhering to stringent standards for security, logging, error handling, performance, and other nonfunctional requirements.

Kafka Kafka Streams Java Spring Boot Tibco AWS Lambda Secrets Manager



Toronto, ON

May 2016 - Sept 2018

- · Managed web pages, email hosting, and web hosting services to ensure seamless client operations and user satisfaction.
- Designed and developed scalable, responsive, and robust web pages optimized for high performance and conversion rates.
- · Collaborated with clients and project managers to define project scope, goals, and deliverables, including SEO optimization strategies.
- · Gathered and analyzed user data to enhance website performance and presented actionable insights to clients.

EDWARD VAISMAN CURRICULUM VITAE

- Delivered detailed software solutions encompassing animations (CSS3, JQuery), scripting (PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Google Apps Scripts), and CMS development (WordPress).
- Built proficiency in time management by consistently meeting tight deadlines across multiple projects.

HTML CSS JavaScript PHP WordPress JQuery Google Apps Scripts SEO

Skills_

Programming Java, Python, Bash, C#, XNA Game Studio

Web HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwindcss, Astro, WordPress, React

Big Data Confluent, Kafka, Flink, Data Hub

Cloud AWS, GCP, Azure, OpenStack, DigitalOcean

DevOps GitHub, GitHub Actions, SemaphoreCI, SaltStack, Terraform, Nomad, Vault, Docker, GitLab, Ansible, Maven

Languages English, Russian.

Education

York University Toronto, ON

B.Sc, Spec. Hons. Computer Science (Software Development)

Sept 2013 - April 2018

EDWARD VAISMAN CURRICULUM VITAE